# 哈佬大家好我是王剛
Hello everyone this is Wang Gang
# 本期視頻我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In this video, I'll share a home cooking dish
# 雜菜炒雞蛋
Mixed veggie with fried egg
# 首先我们准备适量的红薯粉条折断放入盆中
First, let's prepare some sweet potato noodles and place them in a bowl
# 然后加入适量的温水将粉条浸泡30分钟备用
and then add warm water into the bowl, let it soak for 30 minutes
# 同学们也可以用粉丝代替红薯粉
You can also use vermicelli as an alternative
# 准备适量的豆芽放入碗中备用
Prepare some bean sprout in a bowl
# 准备一小把韭菜切成小段备用
Prepare a handful of chinese chives and cut into strips
# 加韭菜的目的增加香味
This is to add fragrance to the dish
# 准备大红椒半个切成细丝备用
Julienne half of a red sweet pepper
# 大红椒不辣属于增香增色
Sweet peppers are not spicy at all. Adding this is to enhance the flavour and colour of this dish.
# 喜欢吃辣的同学可以换成小米辣代替
Those who enjoy spicy food may use "xiao mi la" as an alternative
# 然后准备鸡蛋4个打入碗中搅拌均匀
Prepare and whip 4 eggs evenly.
# 因为鸡蛋比较多 所以搅拌之前需要加入少许的食用盐提前调味
As there are many eggs, we add a pinch of salt to season it in advance.
# 搅拌的时候尽量挑起更多的蛋液方便空气进入
Try to aerate the egg-liquid when whipping.
# 蛋液搅拌均匀之后下一步开始制作
Once completely whipped, let's move on to the next step
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First let's heat up the wok
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的油烧至5成热
once wok is heated, add in some oil and bring it to medium hot.
# 油温5成热之后将准备好的豆芽下锅爆炒几下
When medium hot is reached, lightly stir-fry bean sprout for a few seconds
# 这一步的目的是将豆芽炒脆炒至断生
This is to slightly cook the bean sprout and make it crunchy
# 豆芽断生之后倒出备用
Set aside for later use
# 然后我们再次把锅烧热
Let's heat up the wok again,
# 锅烧热之后加入少许食用油滑锅
Add some oil to grease the wok
# 滑好锅之后将热油倒出加入适量的底油
pour out hot oil and add some base oil
# 下一步开始煎蛋液
Next step is to fry the eggs
# 油温5成热之后将调好的蛋液下锅煎3分钟
Bring the oil to medium hot, fry eggs for 3 minutes
# 这一步的目的是将鸡蛋煎香
This is to fry the egg until the fragrance is brought out
# 中途再翻过另一面煎
Flip over to fry the other side
# 鸡蛋煎香之后搅碎翻炒均匀
Break into small chunks and toss evenly
# 然后加入所有的辅料（韭菜，红椒丝，豆芽，粉条）
Then add in all other ingredients (Chives, capsicum, bean sprout and sweet potato noodles)
# 辅料下锅之后继续翻炒均匀将韭菜炒至断生
Continue toss and stir-fry to slightly cook the chives
# 韭菜断生之后开始调味
Then we start seasoning,
# 锅中加入食用盐1克
Add in 1 gram of salt,
# 加入胡椒粉半勺
half table spoon of ground white pepper,
# 加入少许白糖
a pinch of suger,
# 加入蚝油3克
3 grams of oyster sauce,
# 加入老抽3克调底色
3 grams of dark soy sauce for coloring
# 然后加入生抽酱油4克从锅边淋入翻炒均匀
then add 4 grams of light soy sause along the side of the wok, toss evenly.
# 最后起锅之前再加入少许的香醋炒出锅气即可装盘
Lastly drizzle some vinegar on top then bring out the Wok-hei. Now it is ready to be set on plate.
# 一道非常美味的杂菜炒鸡蛋就制作完成
A very delicious mixed veggie with fried eggs is now complete.
# 【杂菜炒鸡蛋的技术总结】
The technical summaries are as follow
# 第一，豆芽口感爽脆粉条软糯吸味，韭菜增香红椒增色，鸡蛋 金黄干香，这样的搭配非常完美
First, this dish is a perfect combination of the crunchy texture of bean sprouts, flavour of sweet potato noodles, aroma of chives and color of sweet pepper and together with golden brown fragrant fried eggs!
# 第二，在最后起锅的时候加入香醋的目的是增加回味和提鲜
Second, adding in vinegar right before plating is to add another layer of taste and bring out the umami taste
# 第三，此菜没有菜名属于简单家常类别
Third, this home made dish does't have an official name, you can call it whatever you like.
# 杂菜炒鸡蛋的技术总结完毕
The above is everything with this dish.
Follow us on Youtube for more amazing dishes